hey what's up world it's your boy Denzel
and this is
Annabelle we here with that good [__]
yeah that good ass [__] exactly how you
doing today denzo man [__] booted up off
this coffee I'm cooling though what's
your coffee order [__] black coffee no
cream no sugar straight up black coffee
black do we like a medium roast or a
dark roast man I don't know long as it's
black they I'm cool with it what'd you
get up to so far today so far I woke
up easy n n we just you know we walked
over here and everything and just you
know getting ready for this interview
and that's pretty much it just chilling
so far it's your first time in happy99
oh yeah what's your first impression of
this place I mean I like the flip that
they did cuz I'm wearing the um happy99
shirt I like how they did the mark Echo
flip and I like the design and
everything kind of reminds me of jetset
radio you know what I'm saying so yeah I
like it it's super fire I was just
listening to the you ever listen to the
how I built this podcast n n never you
should check them out but I just
listened to the one about Mark Ekko the
guy who started eeko and complex real
goat so shout out to him this is a great
flip yeah it is a really great flip
we're out here in New York getting ready
for the release of your album tonight
right how do you feel man I don't
know n no I know it's going to be a good
thing though cuz like man we got the
club machius thing going on tonight so
we F to all just be in a club partying
doing our thing you know I might do a
song or two I don't know yet but I just
really want everybody to have a good
time and you know what I'm saying like
listen to the project when it comes out
it's going to be a real fun time
listening to that project in the club
I've been able to listen to it over the
last few days goinging into this
interview and the product is incredible
yeah can I ask a question yeah why did I
raise my hand um like what's your
favorite track off the album I like a
lot of them but I really really like
that first track like after that kind of
like intro snippet cuz I really love
that beat really beautiful whoever's
kind of like doing the vocals was that
like a sample or was that like a feature
who was doing that vocal on the beat
that like oh yeah yeah that was U Mickey
de Grand yeah he worked on all my albums
he worked on taboo he worked on zoo he
worked on melt my eyes to your future he
worked on a lot of stuff so yeah shout
out to Mickey because he um the sample
and everything so that's got to be one
of my favorites or what was the other
one I really like I really like G
up I recorded that in New Zealand and
that same session U my boy melow Downs
pulled up shout out to Mellow Downs
Israel osna pulled up as well like he
came to the studio session when I made
that song yeah that's a crazy song I
can't wait to hear that in the club
specifically yeah that [__] going to get
everybody riled up and turned
up crazy I also really like the lunatic
interlude I thought that was really
pretty yeah so the through line on the
project you know cuz we have Kingpin
skinny pimp hosting the whole thing so
he's doing like interludes and all that
stuff and like the intro outro and that
song Pretty much like the segue going in
the SC that was a song that he did off
of skinny pimp volume one and he was
like yo you could sample some of the
stuff du I really wanted to sample stuff
from King of The Players Ball but he was
like nah don't sample that sample this
and then he sent me the tape and then
psychopath and lunatic was the one that
we ended up sampling the whole thing
came together great I wanted to ask you
I think like I don't know I was
listening to lunatic and I was just
seeing all these like little scenes in
my head I think it's like a really
beautiful interlude if that lunatic
interlude was to score like a scene in
like a movie what do you think that
would look like man it would probably be
like a car scene of just [__]
turning up and then getting into some
ratchet ass [__] like gun packing type
[__] you know what I'm saying before
they do something crazy overall I think
it's really interesting to know that
like you put out this first like King of
the mischievous South tape like when you
were 16 I was 17 when cuz I was 16 in
201 you know what I'm saying 2012 was 17
yeah so you were 17 when you put it out
and you come a long way since then it's
been like 12 years since it came out and
it's so cool to see you like take that
sound those influences and bring it back
now when you're really at like the top
of your game and it's like really
refined how does it feel to kind of like
come out with this second edition of
King of the mischievious Heth it feels
good because I tried to do this several
times like I Tred to really make this um
tape like several times and it ended up
becoming something else but the one time
I'm just like you know I'm going to make
this tape and then it sounded like
everything that was from King of mivia
South volume 1 and they was like hey you
don't got to change anything else but
the name so I was like what y want to
change it to so Mark was alluding to
what he wanted me to change it to
without saying the name and I kind of
just like oh I know what you want to
name this and then that's how it went
like that it's cool how it came about
kind of naturally like things always
just kind of happen when they're meant
to yeah I mean trying to make the [__]
and just doesn't come out the way it did
it's like all right you know kind of
gave up on it and then you know you
never know everything kind of resurfaces
later on I heard that you made a lot of
these songs in your bed is that true I
mean couple of them I made in my house
some of them I made overseas and some of
them I made in the studio what is like
your favorite setting to create in if
you had to pick one I don't know like
the studio sometimes you get tired of it
in your house you can record at your
house but the drawback is you can't
invite everybody to your crib overseas
it's just like I like recording over
there cuz it's a different vibe but at
the same time I got to work work work
cuz you know most likely I'm over there
like performing and everything so it
depends it depends do you like recording
around a lot of people or do you prefer
like being more in your Solitude or does
it just depend on what you're making it
depends man if I'm already feeling it
I'm just going to record I kind of got
over that whole like oh I'm I'm afraid
of people in the room type [__] but if I
know I'm not too confident of what I'm
doing I'll tell everybody hey y' y'all
got to leave the room let me figure this
[__] out real quick and then I recording
and I was like okay is it bad okay maybe
I need to fix this or maybe I need to do
this and then when I actually get it
right then I bring everybody in how' you
go about curating all the features on
this album cuz you brought in so many
incredible people we love seeing people
like Armani white on there Tia Ken hot
ones is one of my favorite songs of the
summer for sure how'd you go about
selecting all the people you were going
to collaborate with some of them was
impulse and some of them was team effort
so it's like half and half with that
some just come about with just like
being in a session some of the homies
just come through and they make a song
and the song turns out to be hard and
other one was just like calculated you
know what I'm saying so like hot one
like we I sent that to Ferg and then Tia
was like the last piece there was people
that I wanted to get on this um tape
like when we did CLE pimp with tidal
sign which is a long long story and
originally it was me Juicy J tid alasan
and kayat who was on Ultra [__] right
because at the time ultra [__] wasn't
supposed to be on the project but it was
so good that we wanted to put it on
there we took key off that one talked to
key about it he was like man I'm fine
with that you cool we wanted to put Flo
Millie on that one and it just didn't
come about so a lot of the stuff is
either impulse or calculated I think it
feels like a good mix of everything on
there how did you originally find Tia
Karin like what was your first time
hearing her they sent me um freaky tea
and the song was hard and I seen a video
and it had her and Duke Duce and I was
like all right oh this is fire so I went
and followed her on um Instagram and
stuff like that she followed me back
instantly and then we just started
chatting and started talking about like
making music together so she sent me a
song um I did it and then I remember
when we was talking about hot ones and
it was like yo I think you should get
Tia on this cuz Tia will slide on this I
was like man I [__] with Tia when we met
in person we always yell at each other
and stuff like why you ain't do
this and then when we finally seen each
other like it was literally like you and
it's like you know what I'm saying the
Spider-Man yeah like you and then we
just like and then I remember calling
her and I was like yo I think you would
slide on this and I didn't think she was
going to get the vers done then one day
she just had sent me a picture sent me
the song and sent me her vocals H I got
it done [__] and then that that's how
that happened and she really did that
what's your uh what's your favorite line
from her hot ones verse a no
[Laughter]
she going to kill
me Dollar Thor that is my favorite line
but it was like X [__] let him go cuz
how you broke like every time and I'm
like kind of met her ex though with her
so it was like
damn kind of [__]
up Denzel one of the things that I as a
fan I think a lot of your fans and just
like people in general who are aware of
you and your music really look up to you
for is your ability to be so consistent
throughout your career every album
you've dropped has been a beautiful body
of work you're able to just like
maintain a really high level of art you
continue getting better over the many
years of your career to what would you
attribute your skills of being so
consistent how do you do it I make plans
on plans on plans even if they don't
take form in that moment even when it
came down to like Tabo and Imperial and
everything I always come up with a plan
first and Imperial was supposed to be
the original King of the mivia South
volume 2055 like that was like long time
ago but I always had plans on plans on
plans like I would release this this
this this and this so that's how remain
consistent when I was making taboo I
wanted melt to come out right after that
but I didn't have the emotional
intelligence the um vulnerability the
really express myself of what I'm
actually going through or the maturity
to even do that and then in between I
was just making tracks here and there
and Zoo ended up coming about with Ricky
and I think it took me six months to
make that one it didn't really take that
long for me to make that project yeah
and then mil came after I mean obviously
after unlocking blood and blood out but
I always have plans I just have them in
my notes and I plan everything out put
the all right the tracks track ideas the
imagery how I wanted to look everything
and then talk to the team about it
pretty much um we just cut the fat and
just like okay this makes sense this
makes sense this doesn't make sense we
kind of figure out how to make it make
sense how certain things can be
correlated I like to plan and I like to
execute and I like to study and once I
figure out like okay we got all the bad
stuff out and the mediocre stuff and we
got good stuff we start putting it
together and that's how we pretty much
put it out there a majority of your
planning and brainstorming live like in
your notes app on your phone yes yeah
are there any other tools that you use
for like organization planning or just
things in general that help you stay
consistent and on top of it before that
I was using PowerPoint that's how I
planed Imperial I started to plan more
as I got older I just want to be able to
have things in place it's like
contingency plans like if this don't
work out this is going to work out this
don't work out this is going to work out
this don't work out this is going to
work out if they don't both don't work
out go back to the drawing board outside
of just like your consistency with your
scheduling and like putting these albums
together and it seems like your energy
in your drive is also just really
consistent you're always like really
high energy anytime I see you outside in
the interview anytime you're coming in
your music you have like a really
motivated Pure Energy do you have any
like daily habits or personal habits
that help you keep that energy up
getting punched in the face okay
elaborate getting punched in the face
when and where are you getting punched
in the face in school n but um I just
think like I got to have a mind of being
consistent like going to the martial
arts gym and stuff like that and like
have that kind of consistency and going
to the studio even if I'm not making
anything just being there you know that
was some advice I got long time ago from
either my Muay Tha coaches or just
marking them it was just like yeah just
being consistent even if you don't do
anything even if it's not your best day
like just still go and just kind of keep
doing it what are your tools for battl
in difficult days or days where you're
not feeling motivated where you don't
want to do anything I just sto I just
stop everything and just go live my life
real quick so whenever I'm over music I
just stay home and draw yeah yeah that's
literally what I do and just like watch
movies stuff like that go to museums go
to movies go to the theme park whatever
the case may be you know because you
never know when is going to hit you I
know for me whenever I get tired of a
especially when I get tired of music or
I feel like I've been around a lot of
music listening to it there's certain
artists or like albums I can go to to
kind of hit a refresh kind of just like
refresh my perspective on music do you
have any music that does that for you it
depends man cuz like I could be
listening to rap one day then Rock one
day then I could be listening to R&B
another day then I could be listening to
pop some days you know so it's really
like where my mood is at at that moment
you know that helped me refresh and
everything and I was like okay let me
try something new and then I would like
oh since I'm doing this let me study
what I like from this kind of era and
stuff like that and how can I be able to
push it you know that was like pretty
much the refreshing part just like doing
something new that I never done before
but actually understanding it what have
you been studying recently Rel listening
to like MF Doom albums and stuff like
that but before that I was listening to
like Wham and like revisiting speaker
box love below and 808s and heartbreak
that type of stuff what's your favorite
song on speaker box love below spray it
that's my favorite
too love that are we going to see more
454 collaborations oh we did one the
other day did you yeah we got like we
got a whole song together I could play
it for you after this interview like you
know what I'm saying what does it feel
like yeah
yeah are we going to see any
collaborations with you and pig uh Pig
the Gemini sister hell yeah what your
sister yeah yeah she raw she's crazy
yeah one of my favorite songs they did
together was swiss cheese oh yeah yeah
yeah okay great really looking forward
to hearing that after this interview cuz
that's that's our goat for sure we love
Willie will Willie would you ever
collaborate with pink sefue yes I don't
know why I was listening to the album on
my way over here on my bike and I was
like I really love to hear you do some
stuff with him are there any upcoming
producers that you're loving that you
would like to link up with in the near
future that girl who made not my problem
Lea ran yeah I ran into her like a
couple times definitely will want
production from her more production for
4554 got to throw him in there Cal Banks
like if you guys are familiar with him
me and him got a go record together on
um walking so want to work with him a
lot more I started working with this
other producer named manmade he's pretty
tight and some more stuff with like
working on dying in there in them boys
we'd love to hear all of those okay I'm
going to pop out for a second Quincy's
going to come in and do a segment that
we call Q's Q's Q's Q he has a couple
questions for you all right come on so
we're going to switch places what's up
guys it's Quincy from that good [__] and
and this is Q's Q we're in the happy99
store you know got a lot of anime
Inspirations around us I'm wondering
what anime are you watching right now
one piece okay now see that's that's a
lot because now what AR what what what
Arc of One Piece are you on [__] they
linked up with the um minks and all them
boys oh
yeah okay so you in the jungle with it
yeah yeah they just did the they wait I
might be no you don't I'm not chill
chill chill chill chill chill that they
box just know that they box they they
they get to fight they be fting like the
dogs and the cats and [__] we not going
to say too much but we but you know we
going to talk after we going to talk
after I'm in the 760 yeah type [__] type
[__] I'm like a little bit further than
that I already know what's happenening D
bro there's a
lot we got to cut that out di cut that
out no spoilers man they already know
what's happening there's people spoiling
it right there like [__] it [__] you
know [__] it hey hey
can we just do that can we can we just
say that the enti of One Piece yeah
[__] basically just go on Reddit read
the ending nah don't do it don't do it
okay so do you have a favorite one piece
character and what would that one piece
character's favorite song on the new
project be okay yeah I like um traal
Gala yo what it was like the death surge
surgeon of death or something yeah man
he be making rooms cutting people heads
off flipping them and [__] like that
and he's smart he be like three moves
ahead I also [__] with the polar bear in
that crew too oh no he be be fighting
bro I a going to lie he be fting I think
who you think will win out of him and
Chopper see like that's the thing like I
feel like the polar bear Will Come Out
Swinging if Chopper really gets to that
point like okay I really got to boss up
then you know he going with the floor
like for sure I think um troga lost some
where either be g's up or set it like
it's out of those two but like N I think
like you see how Chopper be fighting now
like you know what I'm saying he got to
kind of got the [__] under control with
all that stuff and he be doing the like
little Kung Fu [__] now so I'm like yeah
Chopper could transform like the polar
bear he just you know he just be
fighting right I mean the polar bear got
hands but now once Chopper like levels
up on you it's over I ain't going to lie
they they both be boxing what else I
want to talk about is kind of like the
comic book aesthetic theme of unlock the
I'm with Kenny beats I just want to know
like what that was like crafting that
world with Kenny beats and you know
obviously like the cave episode you see
Annabelle got the GD weedies
on she got a whole G she got the cook GD
weedies on yo how how many pair of GD
weedies do you have man I got several
pairs of GD weedies at the crib you know
what I'm saying shout out to S boo you
know so when we made the cave we started
working on the project right there it
took us like two to three days from my
part and then I was just with Kenny and
Kenny was like it really took five days
bro he was like it took three days for
you but it took 5 days for him cuz he
had to do all the production and
everything and then I remember when we
was in those sessions and we was was
like Hey nameing the tracks and all that
stuff and it's was like yeah this going
to feel like leak fouls cuz we don't
have no single on it and you know the
song that everybody like is Diet you
know man I was telling him like we going
to do this we going to do this we going
to do this and he was like all right
whatever cuz he he don't believe it
until he sees it the thing was when we
started hitting up like yep we about to
film this we about to do this oh and
it's goingon to be half this and half
cartoon stuff like that right and he was
just like oh this is really happening so
us filming it and then them animating it
going through different animators shout
out to P films they the ones who like
put it together and then you know the
team we put the comic book together and
the toys also you know we need to put
some unlocked toys in here to be honest
yo bro send the package through we got
to get happy99 Denzel Curry Kenny beats
action figures right there we was just
looking at it like hey doom and them for
the like mad villain album with all caps
and all that stuff they had toys you
know what I'm saying Jay um Diller had
toys for the donuts I just felt like we
was in that world so we was like man we
need to have toys and Comics no
absolutely I really [__] with the
animation style of the music video and I
was wondering like if there was like any
anime in specific that kind of inspired
that like you were watching at the time
that kind of inspired that creation of
the visuals or like any mood board kind
of things that you had going on well it
was a combination of things when it came
down to making unlock what inspired the
animation style was like Boomerang
Cartoon Network Adult Swim that's why
you see stuff that look like Samurai
Jack for like specific ones like diet
that was supposed to be drawn in gorilla
style like the gorillas and then we had
other ones that was supposed to be like
animated like on some Jimmy Neutron [__]
which didn't happen cowboy bbop and
Anime you got to add the anime
influences in there but we couldn't get
all the art that wanted so it was like
pretty much the same guy running it all
over again you know definitely I mean I
[__] with all those shows uh genedy
tarkovski I think his name is yeah yeah
yeah the guy who animated Samurai Jack
yeah he did Samurai Jack he used to work
on Powerpuff Girls did you see his did
you see his new anime oh Primal yeah
Primal tarasi is like everybody's
childhood you know so when they came
back with like Sam Jack and everything
it was like um damn like we adults cuz
you know he didn't really kill nobody
when we was kids but when you watching
as an adult and you see him like murder
somebody you like oh [__] no like they
they was really drama now especially
like when they did the time skip too
like he was really boxing he was really
yeah he was in the paint you know he was
still killing robots and [__] but like
when he merked a human I was like
oh
damn oh they really kill [__] in this
show they really merked the [__]
in this show
man I was um on my homies page I don't
know yall know him his name Carl Jones
Carl Jones is um he plays Thugnificent
on The Boondocks and everything and he
like um draws and he was like one of the
writers on the boond Ducks too he was
talking about like him working at
Cartoon Network and everything and like
he had the voice actor from Cow and
Chicken on the show and then when you
think about the intro it's like Mama had
a chicken mama had a cow there was proud
he didn't care how I was
like this is beastiality [__] about it
like like that [__] yo Cartoon Network
had some weird messages in their
cartoons weird ass messages I [__] with
Regular Show though because they had
some like hidden messages but it was
pretty much just like sit around and
drink a beer kind of thing yeah he just
disguised it with sodas and stuff like
that he was like what the H bro I
remember watching that I was like oh I
like this show it was like Regular Show
and Adventure Time those were the shows
I was like yeah I'm watching this but
you know if we going back to the to the
old school they had like whatever
Happened to Robot Jones Ed and Edy why
am I for and Eddie that's like one of
those 1:00 a.m. just like cuss for me
where it's just like that's how I knew I
was up late when like Ed and Eddie was
on I was like yo this is a freaky
cartoon see I used to watch um Boomerang
with my dad and um his favorite show was
Johnny Quest yo Johnny Quest is fire you
ever seen kick batowski who the hell is
that it's like like the same style
except he's like a stunt man and he does
like dirt bike tricks they look he like
animated the hell out of his
butt all right I got to get to these
questions we talking about comic books
later bro also wanted to talk about was
the remix unlock 1.5 and like the
producers and the features that you had
on that kind of like remix tape how did
you kind of like Foster your personal
relationships with those producers and
those artists to like kind of bring them
together and like what was it like kind
of curating that lineup to like refresh
the album well that was mainly the team
it was just like look we F to send it
to and majority of them were all the
homies so it was just like like all
right Jay faace you know Robert Glasper
uh Alchemist Charlie heat like just
sending them to all those guys and then
bringing in like my cousin Smo bringing
in Kenny Mason bringing in all these
guys to remix all of them it was like a
group effort thing you know just like
talking to everybody and everything
because I remember hitting up Joey and
Joey was like oh I got the track bro I'm
about to do it hitting up Kenny was like
Kenny I'm about to do it and then
talking with Smo and then that song that
we did the so incredible remix is
personally me I love that song more than
any the song that's on the 1.5 and
that's how me and him found out we was
cousins word dang that's crazy so like
kind of building off of that like what
did you take away from the overall
experience of just kind of like like I
said like refreshing that album and like
getting together a bunch of features and
producers to kind of remix that album
how did that carry over into your new
album today just like what did you learn
from that experience nothing damn you
know cuz they're two separate things
that's the only reason but like I would
just say like the experiences in me like
evolving as an MC that's what carried
over as opposed to the production but at
the same time you got people that was on
unlocked that's still producing on this
one you know cuz Charlie heat did Scar
you know what I'm saying you know I want
to SM on this um tape too but you know
it's going to happen eventually when the
time comes you know he was busy and I
was just kind of just getting things
together you know yeah but um yeah I
think the only thing that carried over
was like um me learning to be a better
MC final question Annabelle asked on
Twitter people like what people wanted
to know from denel Curry you we're here
we're here it's not an anime question
it's not an anime question I swear to
God I swear to God bro bro we can shake
on it do you want to shake on it I don't
when is unlocked 2.0 happening oh damn
never like can't you can't even like
give us a little bit of Hope be like oh
just like not right now [__] not
happening what about like later you know
no Kenny can you text him I was just
[__] you got you got me for a
second and you know this
man no no but for real though it's not
happening I'm just [__] with yall
it's going to happen at some point just
not now so are there any other kind of
like producer collab albums you got in
the works well shoot Flo hit me up he
wanted to do something [__] I was
working with Hit Boy for a minute we
just going to see what happens even
talking to Cal Banks about like doing a
collab project with him later on Yo Cal
Banks is fire I know we all want a yase
curry album you know we could do like a
black samurai I just called the Yas
curry in my head my fault I didn't mean
to put that on you I mean [__] hey look
man you feel me you feel
me nah but no we going to figure it out
like you just I'm just making [__] right
now so just going to see what comes in
flourish it might be a collab album
might not be absolutely well I'm excited
to hear what you guys have cooking up I
feel like every time you guys link up
it's magic and so I'm really excited
what you got coming up in addition to
this album but I'm also really excited
for the album to Dro tonight yeah it's
it's about to be one of them ones so
thank you whoever was watching thank
this guy Q thank Annabelle this that
good
[__] all right that's Q's Q actually we
we completely done you know that's it
have anything else you want to say make
sure you get the album and drop tonight
July 19th it drops at 12:00 a.m. get
that listen to it hit me back goddamn
come to the show suicide boys going on
tour that is me Denzel last name Curry
middle name rayon what they call me big
Ultra what I get money from where my
sofa all right we out yeah